export const GENERALKNOWLEDGEINARTSA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. When one takes a critical look at a variety of objects the following properties are noted",
A: "Sweetness, bitterness & taste",
B: "Loudness, softness & distance",
C: "Smell, aroma and odour",
D: "Shapes, colours and textures",
answer: "D. Shapes, colours and textures",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following will produce the shade of a colour?",
A: "Black",
B: "Grey",
C: "Tin",
D: "White",
answer: "A. Black",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A creative person is characterized by",
A: "Temperament and haste.",
B: "Ideas and uncertainty.",
C: "Hard-work and imagination.",
D: "Chaos and disorder.",
answer: "C. Hard-work and imagination.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The caveman carved figures mainly in",
A: "Wood and rubber.",
B: "Bone and wood.",
C: "Stone and bone.",
D: "Rubber and stone.",
answer: "C. Stone and bone.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The part that seems to be of greatest visual appeal in a work of art is",
A: "Balanced area",
B: "Foreground",
C: "Background",
D: "Focal area",
answer: "D. Focal area",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The presentation of a stool to a woman during marriage is a practice in connection with",
A: "Ancestor veneration.",
B: "Belief in spirits.",
C: "Rites of passage.",
D: "Belief in animism.",
answer: "C. Rites of passage.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following is credited to the Hellenistic period of Greed art?",
A: "Doric style of architecture was invented",
B: "Landscape painting was invented",
C: "Corinthian style of architecture was invented",
D: "Picture-writing was invented",
answer: "C. Corinthian style of architecture was invented",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which part of the paper-mulberry tree is tapa produced from?",
A: "Bark",
B: "Gum",
C: "Leaves",
D: "Root",
answer: "A. Bark",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Linseed oil and turpentine are used in mixing",
A: "Acrylic paint.",
B: "Emulsion",
C: "Oil colour.",
D: "Gouache",
answer: "C. Oil colour.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following is a monoprint?",
A: "Frottage",
B: "Lino-cut",
C: "Marbling",
D: "Wood-cut",
answer: "A. Frottage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The art movement which placed emphasis on cultural values was",
A: "Expressionism.",
B: "Humanism.",
C: "Impressionism.",
D: "Surrealism.",
answer: "B. Humanism.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A stipple is a tool used to create",
A: "Colours",
B: "Dots",
C: "Lines",
D: "Spaces",
answer: "B. Dots",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following expresses personal emotions or thoughts?",
A: "Appellation",
B: "Dirge",
C: "Lyric",
D: "Praise-name",
answer: "C. Lyric",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Negative spaces of the images traced onto a silk screen are",
A: "Painted black.",
B: "Left unblocked.",
C: "Dabbed with printing paste.",
D: "Blocked with lacquer.",
answer: "B. Left unblocked.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Guernica was painted by",
A: "a Spanish",
B: "a French.",
C: "an English",
D: "an Italian.",
answer: "A. a Spanish",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following is a preliminary drawing?",
A: "Descriptive drawing",
B: "Tonal drawing",
C: "Illustration drawing",
D: "Sketch drawing",
answer: "D. Sketch drawing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Hard steel is used to sink lines into the plate surface in",
A: "Embossing",
B: "Engraving",
C: "Etching",
D: "In laying",
answer: "B. Engraving",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following is a description of the style of an individual artist?",
A: "Rose period",
B: "Archaic period",
C: "Renaissance period",
D: "Classical period",
answer: "A. Rose period",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. When the twill weave is used, the product that comes out is",
A: "Calico",
B: "Check",
C: "Gabardine",
D: "Poplin",
answer: "C. Gabardine",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A series of drawings made to explain a process is",
A: "Continuous drawing",
B: "Illustrative drawing",
C: "Descriptive drawing",
D: "Range drawing",
answer: "C. Descriptive drawing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. In traditional belief, ancestors are called for help through",
A: "Libation, drumming and offering",
B: "Offering, purification and abstinence",
C: "Prayer, lamentation and fasting",
D: "Pacification, ablution and cleansing",
answer: "A. Libation, drumming and offering",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The focus of the ancient Egyptian art was",
A: "The life of the ordinary Egyptian",
B: "River transport on the Nile",
C: "Everlasting life in the hereafter",
D: "Cultural activities in the rural areas",
answer: "C. Everlasting life in the hereafter",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Islamic art has always been restricted to",
A: "Geometric ornament and calligraphy",
B: "Text writing and sculpture",
C: "Calligraphy and block lettering",
D: "Figurative ornament and calligraphy",
answer: "A. Geometric ornament and calligraphy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A beautiful picture has",
A: "A psychological value",
B: "An intrinsic value",
C: "A religious value",
D: "A material value",
answer: "A. A psychological value",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Archaeologists use art to analyse discoveries by",
A: "Material",
B: "Style",
C: "Function",
D: "Preservation",
answer: "B. Style",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The Coptic writing was composed of combination of",
A: "Egyptian and Greek letters",
B: "Roman and English letters",
C: "Islamic and Egyptian letters",
D: "Egyptian and Roman letters",
answer: "A. Egyptian and Greek letters",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Benin court art usually takes the form of",
A: "Painting",
B: "Pottery",
C: "Sculpture",
D: "Textiles",
answer: "C. Sculpture",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Early Greek paintings that have survived till today are those made",
A: "Walls and panels",
B: "Vases and panels",
C: "Jugs and walls",
D: "Vases and jugs",
answer: "B. Vases and panels",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. An art patron is someone who",
A: "Advises an artist",
B: "Sells work of art",
C: "Commissions works of art",
D: "Is sponsored to produce art",
answer: "C. Commissions works of art",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Green is warm as it approaches",
A: "Blue",
B: "Red",
C: "Violet",
D: "Yellow",
answer: "B. Red",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The major characteristics of African carving is",
A: "Abstraction",
B: "Movement",
C: "Naturalism",
D: "Realism",
answer: "A. Abstraction",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. In which of these countries was the human figure painted in profile?",
A: "China",
B: "Crete",
C: "Egypt",
D: "Ghana",
answer: "C. Egypt",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following colours is good for impasto?",
A: "Water colour",
B: "Oil colour",
C: "Acrylic colour",
D: "Poster colour",
answer: "B. Oil colour",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following processes is associated with leatherwork?",
A: "Centering",
B: "Scorching",
C: "Modeling",
D: "Throwing",
answer: "D. Tanning",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Colour printing is uniquely the art form of the",
A: "Chinese",
B: "Egyptians",
C: "Indians",
D: "Japanese",
answer: "A. Chinese",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. What feeling, does blue convey?",
A: "Bravery",
B: "Freshness",
C: "Quietness",
D: "Warmth",
answer: "C. Quietness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Planography, relief and intaglio are processes associated with",
A: "Ceramics",
B: "Jewellery",
C: "Printing",
D: "Sculpture",
answer: "C. Printing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. An artist accidentally mixes red and green to produce",
A: "Complementary colour",
B: "Tertiary colour",
C: "Neutral colour",
D: "Harmonious colour",
answer: "C. Neutral colour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Polynesian art-expression consists of the making of",
A: "Figurines",
B: "Jewellery",
C: "Mats",
D: "Pots",
answer: "C. Mats",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Beadmaking is one of the major works of the",
A: "Akwapims",
B: "Krobos",
C: "Shais",
D: "Fantes",
answer: "C. Shais",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]